<?xml version="1.0"?>
<aesop>
    <fable> The orator Demades was trying to address his Athenian audience. When he failed to get their attention, he asked if he might tell them an Aesop's fable. The audience agreed, so Demades began his story. 'The goddess Demeter, a swallow, and an eel were walking together down the road. When they reached a river, the swallow flew up in the air and the eel jumped into the water.' Demades then fell silent. The audience asked, 'And what about the goddess Demeter?' 'As for Demeter,' Demades replied, 'she is angry at all of you for preferring Aesop's fables to politics!' </fable>
    <fable> They say that during an assembly in Athens, Demosthenes was prevented from making his speech, so he told the audience he wanted to say just a few words. When the audience had fallen silent, Demosthenes began his tale. 'It was summertime, and a young man had hired a donkey to take him from Athens to Megara. At midday, when the sun was blazing hot, the young man and the donkey's driver both wanted to sit in the donkey's shadow. They began to jostle one another, fighting for the spot in the shade. The driver maintained that the man had rented the donkey but not his shadow, while the young man claimed that he had rented both the donkey and all the rights thereto.' Having told this much of the story, Demosthenes then turned his back on the audience and began to walk away. The Athenians shouted at him to stop and begged him to finish the story. 'Indeed!' said Demosthenes. 'You want to hear all about the donkey's shadow, but you refuse to pay attention when someone talks to you about serious matters!'</fable>
    <fable>A comfortably plump dog happened to run into a wolf. The wolf asked the dog where he had been finding enough food to get so big and fat. 'It is a man,' said the dog, 'who gives me all this food to eat.' The wolf then asked him, 'And what about that bare spot there on your neck?' The dog replied, 'My skin has been rubbed bare by the iron collar which my master forged and placed upon my neck.' The wolf then jeered at the dog and said, 'Keep your luxury to yourself then! I don't want anything to do with it, if my neck will have to chafe against a chain of iron!'</fable>
    <fable>An onager saw a donkey standing in the sunshine. The onager approached the donkey and congratulated him on his good physical condition and excellent diet. Later on, the onager saw that same donkey bearing a load on his back and being harried by a driver who was beating the donkey from behind with a club. The onager then declared, 'Well, I am certainly not going to admire your good fortune any longer, seeing as you pay such a high price for your prosperity!'</fable>
    <fable>An onager saw a donkey labouring under a heavy load and he made fun of the donkey's enslavement. 'Lucky me!' said the onager. 'I am free from bondage and do not have to work for anyone else, since I have grass near at hand on the hillsides, while you rely on someone else to feed you, forever oppressed by slavery and its blows!' At that very moment a lion happened to appear on the scene. He did not come near the donkey since the donkey's driver was standing beside him. The onager, however, was all alone, so the lion attacked and devoured him. </fable>
    <fable>The Galli, those priests of the goddess Cybebe, used a donkey to carry their luggage when they went around begging for alms. When their donkey finally died, overcome by work and the whip, they stripped his hide and made themselves some tambourines. When someone asked them what they had done with their darling donkey, the priests replied, 'He thought that once he died he would get some rest, but he keeps on getting beaten just the same!'</fable>
    <fable>A slave who was running away from his cruel master happened to meet Aesop, who knew him as a neighbour. 'What's got you so excited?' asked Aesop. 'Father Aesop -- a name you well deserve since you are like a father to me -- I'm going to be perfectly frank, since you can be safely trusted with my troubles. There's plenty of whipping and not enough food. I'm constantly sent on errands out to the farm without any provisions for the journey. If the master dines at home, I have to wait on him all night long; if he is invited somewhere else, I have to lie outside in the gutter until dawn. I should have earned my freedom by now, but my hairs have gone gray and I'm still slaving away. If I had done anything to deserve this, I would stop complaining and suffer my fate in silence. But the fact is that I never get enough to eat and my cruel master is always after me. For these reasons, along with others that it would take too long to tell you, I've decided to go wherever my feet will lead me.' 'Well,' said Aesop, 'listen to what I say: if you must endure such hardship without having done anything wrong, as you say, then what is going to happen to you now that you really are guilty of something?' With these words of advice, Aesop scared the slave into giving up his plans of escape.</fable>
    <fable>A man caught a jackdaw and tied the bird's foot with a piece of string so that he could give the bird to his children as a present. The jackdaw, however, could not stand to live in human society, so when they let him loose for just a moment, he ran away. But when he got back to his nest, the string became entangled in the branches, so that the jackdaw was unable to fly. As he was dying, the bird said to himself, 'How stupid of me! Since I could not stand being a slave in human society, I have brought about my own death.' </fable>
    <fable>A shepherd and a butcher were walking along the road together. They saw a plump little lamb who had wandered away from the flock and had been left behind by his fellow sheep. The shepherd and the butcher both rushed to grab the lamb. This was back in the days when animals spoke the same language as people, so the lamb asked the two men why they wanted to grab him and carry him off. After the lamb found out what they both did, he turned and offered himself to the shepherd. 'You are nothing but an executioner of sheep,' he said to the butcher, 'and your hands are stained with the blood of the flock! This man, on the other hand, rejoices if we thrive and prosper.'</fable>
    <fable>There was a donkey who worked for a gardener. Because the gardener made the donkey work very hard but gave him very little food, the donkey prayed to Zeus to take him away from the gardener and give him to another master, so Zeus sent Hermes to sell the donkey to a potter. The donkey also found this situation unbearable, since he was forced to carry even heavier loads than before. He called upon Zeus again, and this time Zeus arranged for the donkey to be purchased by a tanner. When the donkey saw the kind of work the tanner did, he said, 'Oh, it would have been better for me to have kept on working for my previous masters in a state of starvation! Now I have ended up in a place where I won't even get a proper burial after I die.' </fable>
    <fable>A cowardly old man had led his donkey out to pasture. At the unexpected sound of the enemy approaching, the old man was stricken with terror and tried to persuade the donkey to run away so that he wouldn't be captured. The donkey obstinately asked the old man, 'Tell me, do you suppose the victor will make me carry two pack saddles instead of one?' The old man said he did not think so. 'I rest my case,' concluded the donkey. 'What difference does it make who my master is, if I always carry one saddle at a time?'</fable>
    <fable>A frog looked out from her pond and saw a battle taking place between the bulls. 'Oh no!' she said, 'There is terrible danger in store for us.' Another frog asked her why she said this, since the bulls were fighting for control of the herd in their home far away from the frogs. The first frog explained, 'While their habitat may be separate from ours and our species not the same, the bull who is driven from the lordship of the meadow will come to find a secret hiding place here in the marsh, crushing us beneath his heavy hooves. That is why their frenzy is a matter of life and death for us!'</fable>
    <fable>The lion had gone into in a raging frenzy. A fawn saw him from the woods and said, 'Oh, we really are in trouble! Now that the lion is enraged, he will not stop at anything - and he was already more than we could bear even before he went out of his mind!'

</fable>
    <fable>A cow and a she-goat and a long-suffering sheep decided to become the lion's companions. They went into the forest together and there they caught an extremely large stag which they divided into four portions. Then the lion said, 'I claim the first portion by right of my title, since I am called the king; the second portion you will give me as your partner; then, because I am strongest, the third portion is mine ... and woe betide anyone who dares to touch the fourth!' In this way the wicked lion carried off all the spoils for himself.</fable>
    <fable>The lion, the wolf, and the fox agreed to go hunting together. The fox caught a goose, the wolf caught a fat ram, and the lion caught a scrawny cow. Then it was time to eat. The lion told the wolf to divide their catch. The wolf said, 'Let each one take what he has caught: the lion will take the cow, I'll take the ram, and the fox will take the goose.' The lion was enraged and, raising his paw, he used his claws to strip the wolf's head of all its fur and skin. The lion then ordered the fox to divide the spoils. The fox said, 'My lord, you should eat as much of the fat ram as you want, since its meat is tender, then you should eat as much of the goose as you want, but you should eat the cow's flesh only in moderation, since it is so tough. Whatever is left over you can give to us, your servants.' 'Well done,' said the lion. 'Who taught you how to do such a good job of dividing the spoils?' The fox said, 'My lord, I have learned from my associate's red cap: his excoriated skull provides a very vivid lesson.'</fable>
    <fable>When the lion made himself king of the beasts, he wanted to be known for his fairness, so he gave up his old habits and contented himself with a limited diet just as the other animals did, committed to dispensing justice with complete honesty. As time went by, however, the lion's resolution began to waver. Since he was not able to alter his natural inclinations, he began to take certain animals aside in private and ask them whether or not his breath smelled bad. It was a clever strategy: the animals who said that it smelled bad and the animals who said it did not were all killed just the same and the lion was thus able to satisfy his appetite. After he had slaughtered a number of the animals in this way, the lion turned to the monkey and asked how his breath smelled. The monkey exclaimed that the lion's breath smelled of cinnamon, as if it were the very altar of the gods. The lion was ashamed to slaughter someone who said such nice things, so he changed his tactics and fooled the monkey with a newly devised stratagem. The lion pretended that he was sick. The doctors came right away, of course, and when they checked the lion's veins and found that his pulse was normal, they ordered him to eat some food that would be light on his stomach, thus alleviating his nausea. 'Kings may eat what they like,' admitted the lion. 'And I've never tried monkey meat... I would like to have a taste of that.' No sooner said than done: the obsequious monkey was quickly killed so that the lion could eat him immediately. </fable>
    <fable>The lion had grown old and sick and was lying in his cave. All the animals, except for the fox, had come to visit their king. The wolf seized this opportunity to denounce the fox in front of the lion, complaining that the fox showed no respect for the lion, who was the common master of them all. Indeed, the fox had not even come to pay the ailing lion a visit! The fox arrived just in time to hear the end of the wolf's speech. The lion roared at the fox, but the fox asked for a chance to explain herself. 'After all,' said the fox, 'which one of all the animals assembled here has helped you as I have, travelling all over the world in order to seek out and discover from the doctors a remedy for your illness?' The lion ordered the fox to describe the remedy immediately, and the fox replied, 'You must flay a living wolf and wrap yourself in his skin while it is still warm.' When the wolf had been killed, the fox laughed and said, 'It is better to put your master in a good mood, not a bad one.' 
The story shows that someone who plots against others falls into his own trap.</fable>
    <fable>A lion had grown old and weak. He pretended to be sick, which was just a ruse to make the other animals come pay their respects so that he could eat them all up, one by one. The fox also came to see the lion, but she greeted him from outside the cave. The lion asked the fox why she didn't come in. The fox replied, 'Because I see the tracks of those going in, but none coming out.' </fable>
    <fable>There was a lion who strove to emulate the best sort of life lived in human society. He made his home inside a spacious den and tried to show genuine kindness to all those whom he recognized as the elite beasts of the mountain. His den often hosted a large crowd of such animals, who gathered together in a company and treated one another with civility. The lion would befriend and entertain them according to the rules of hospitality, placing before each of his guests their favourite dish, made with ingredients that the lion knew would give them pleasure. There was a fox who lived with the lion as his friend and companion, and the two of them were very happy together. Meanwhile, an elderly monkey served as the carver at the feasts, distributing the portions of meat to the lion's guests at dinner. Whenever there was a guest who was not one of the regular party, the monkey would set before him the same portion which he offered his master, namely, the quarry that the lion had seized in his latest hunting expedition. On these occasions, the fox received leftovers from the day before, and less than her usual portion. One day the lion happened to notice that the fox was pointedly refusing to speak and that she refrained from the meat served at dinner. The lion asked her what was the matter. 'My wise fox,' said the lion, 'speak to me as you used to do! Cheer up and take part in the banquet, my dear.' But the fox said, 'O lion, best among all the species of beasts, I am sick at heart and deeply worried. It is not only the present situation that distresses me; I am also saddened by things which I see are yet to come. If some new guest arrives with every passing day, one after the other, this will become a matter of custom and soon I will not even have leftover meat for my dinner.' The lion was amused and smiled a lion's smile. 'Blame the monkey for all that,' he said. 'It is his fault, not mine.'</fable>
    <fable>There was once a lion king who did not have a bad temper. In fact, he never took any pleasure in acting violently but was instead mild and just, as if he were a human being. During this lion's reign, so they say, all the wild animals assembled to present their petitions and receive verdicts in their disputes. Every animal was called to account: the wolf for what he had done to the lamb, the leopard for what she had done to the wild goat, the tiger for what he had done to the deer, and so on. In the end, all the animals were at peace with one another. The timid hare then proclaimed, 'Now has come the day for which I have always prayed, when even the weak creatures are feared by the strong!'</fable>
    <fable>Only a ridiculous person would try to make laws to govern the most superior members of a society. Indeed, those gods among men would probably respond as did the lions in the story of Antisthenes when the hares harangued the assembly, holding that everyone was to be considered of equal worth.</fable>
    <fable>There were once some birds who gathered together for a group assembly and debated amongst themselves who was best suited to rule. The peacock said to the other birds, 'The kingship suits me best, since I am remarkably beautiful and in the prime of life.' While the rest of the birds were satisfied with the peacock, the raven made his way into their midst and protested, 'Tell me, if you become king, what is going to happen when the eagle attacks us: are you strong enough to rescue us from his assault?' </fable>
    <fable>The dumb beasts wanted to elect a king from amongst their ranks. The camel and the elephant were the two leading candidates because of their size and their strength. The monkey, however, argued that they were both unqualified. 'The camel cannot rule us because she doesn't have the guts to fight against those who step out of line,' said the monkey, 'and there is also a potential danger if the elephant is king: how will he defend us from the little pigs?' </fable>
    <fable>At an assembly of the dumb beasts, the monkey did a dance. The performance was a great success and the animals elected the monkey to be their king. But the fox was jealous of the monkey, so when she saw some meat lying in a trap, she led the monkey there and told him that she had found a treasure. The fox explained that she had not taken it for herself because of the king's prerogative. Instead, she had guarded this royal prize just for him. She then told the monkey to go ahead and take it. The monkey recklessly put his hand in the trap and was caught. When he accused the fox of luring him into an ambush, the fox replied, 'O you monkey! How can you rule over the dumb beasts when you yourself are such an idiot?' </fable>
    <fable>The doves kept having to run away from the kite, eluding death on the swiftness of their wings. The rapacious kite then decided to try some deceptive advice, fooling the defenceless flock by means of a trick. “Why do you prefer this anxious way of life,” he asked, “when instead you could strike up an agreement with me and make me your king, so that I would keep you safe from all possible danger?” The doves were persuaded by the kite's advice and turned themselves over to his care but once he became king, the kite began to feast on his subjects one by one, wielding supreme authority with the fierceness of his talons. Then one of the survivors said, “This is the punishment we deserve, since we put our lives in the hands of this thieving scoundrel!”</fable>
    <fable>The trees came together so that they could anoint a king to rule over them. 'Please be our ruler,' they said to the olive tree. The olive tree said in reply, 'Why would I abandon the richness of my oil, which is valued by both gods and mortals, in order to become the leader of the trees?' They came to the fig tree and said, 'Agree to rule over us.' The fig tree answered, 'Why would I relinquish my sweetness and delightful fruit in order to become the leader of the trees?' They came to the vine, hoping that the vine might rule over them, but the vine answered, 'Why would I relinquish the wine which brings joy both to God and to mankind?' And so the vine refused to be their leader. The trees then said to the thorn bush, 'Rule over us.' The thorn bush replied, 'If indeed you have resolved to make me your king, come and rest under my shadow, and if you refuse, a fire will come forth from the thorn bush and devour the cedars of Lebanon!'</fable>
    <fable>While the frogs were hopping about in the freedom of their pond they began shouting to Jupiter that they wanted a king who could hold their dissolute habits in check. Jupiter laughed and bestowed on the frogs a small piece of wood which he dropped all of a sudden into their pond. As the wood splashed lightly into the water, it terrified the timid frogs. They plunged into the mud and hid there a long time until one frog happened to raise her head cautiously up out of the water. After studying the king, she summoned the other frogs. Putting aside their fear, the frogs all raced over and began jumping on the piece of wood, rudely making fun of it. When the frogs had showered their king with shame and scorn, they asked Jupiter to send them another one. Jupiter was angry that they had made fun of the king he had given them, so he sent them a water-snake, who killed the frogs one by one with her piercing sting. As the water-snake was happily eating her fill, the useless creatures ran away, speechless in their fright. They secretly sent a message to Jupiter through Mercury, begging him to put a stop to the slaughter but Jupiter replied, 'Since you rejected what was good in order to get something bad, you better put up with it - or else something even worse might happen!'</fable>
    <fable>A certain abbot gave his monks three-course meals but the monks said, 'This abbot gives us too little to eat. Let us pray to God that he will die soon.' Whether for this reason or for some other reason, the abbot soon died. He was replaced by another abbot, and this new abbot gave them two-course meals. The monks were angry and upset, so they said 'Now we must pray even harder that God will deprive this man of his life, because he has deprived us of one of our courses.' The abbot then died. He was replaced by a third abbot, who took away yet another course. The angry monks said, 'This one is the worst of all: he is starving us to death! Let us pray to God that he will die soon.' Then one of the monks said, 'Meanwhile, I will pray to God that he give this abbot a long life and keep him safe on our behalf.' The others were surprised and asked him why he said this. The monk explained, 'I see that our first abbot was bad, the second one worse, and this third abbot is the worst of all. I am afraid that when this one dies, he will be replaced by one who is even worse, and then we really will die of starvation!' </fable>
    <fable>Aesop was defending a demagogue at Samos who was on trial for his life when he told this story: 'A fox was crossing a river but she got swept by the current into a gully. A long time passed and she couldn't get out. Meanwhile, there were ticks swarming all over the fox's body, making her quite miserable. A hedgehog wandered by and happened to see the fox. He took pity on her and asked if he should remove the ticks, but the fox refused. The hedgehog asked the reason why, and the fox replied, "These ticks have taken their fill of me and are barely sucking my blood at this point, but if you take these ticks away, others will come and those hungry new ticks will drink up all the blood I have left!" And the same is true for you, people of Samos: this man will do you no harm since he is already wealthy, but if you condemn him to death, others will come who do not have any money, and they will rob you blind!'</fable>
    <fable>The wolves wanted to make friends with the dogs, so they said, 'Since we have so much in common, why don't you treat us as your brothers and friends? It is merely our attitude that divides us. We wolves all live a life of freedom, while you dogs are the slaves of people who make you wear collars around your necks and who beat you with sticks whenever it pleases them. And that is not your only hardship: you even have to guard their flocks and, what's worse, when they are eating their dinner, they toss you nothing but the bones as your share. If you will agree to our bargain, you can turn everything over to us and we'll eat our fill together.' Right away the dogs agreed, so the wolves attacked the flock and killed the dogs, so that the flock could not call out for help against the wolves. 
The fable shows that these are the wages of people who betray their country.</fable>
    <fable>The wolves sent messengers to the sheep, offering to swear a sacred oath of everlasting peace if the sheep would just agree to hand over the dogs for punishment. It was all because of the dogs, said the wolves, that the sheep and the wolves were at war with one another. The flock of sheep, those foolish creatures who bleat at everything, were ready to send the dogs away but there was an old ram among them whose deep fleece shivered and stood on end. 'What kind of negotiation is this!' he exclaimed. 'How can I hope to survive in your company unless we have guards? Even now, with the dogs keeping watch, I cannot graze in safety.'</fable>
    <fable>The sheep and the wolves were at war with one another but the sheep could not be defeated because the dogs' protection kept them safe. The wolves sent ambassadors to the sheep, pretending to offer an end to the hostilities if the sheep would let the wolves serve as their guardians. Hoping that this would establish an accord once and for all, the sheep agreed to all the wolves' demands. Afterwards, the wolves broke the treaty and were able to devour the sheep now that they no longer had anyone to protect them. The sheep recognized their error too late and regretted the decision they had made. </fable>
    <fable>A wolf had been mauled by dogs and had cast himself down on the ground. Because of his injuries, the wolf could not go in search of food, so when he saw a sheep, he begged her to bring him something to drink from the river that ran nearby. 'If you just give me something to drink,' said the wolf, 'I will find myself something to eat.' The sheep replied, 'But if I give you with something to drink, then you will make me your dinner as well!' </fable>
    <fable>A shepherd found some wolf cubs and he brought them up, thinking that the fully grown wolves would both guard his flock and steal other people's sheep to bring back to his sheepfold. But when the cubs grew up, the first thing they did was to destroy the man's own flock. The man groaned and said, 'It serves me right! Why didn't I kill them when they were little?' </fable>
    <fable>A shepherd found a little wolf cub and raised it. Then, when the cub was bigger he taught it to steal from his neighbours' flocks. Once he had learned how to do this, the wolf said to the shepherd, 'Now that you have shown me how to steal, take care that many of your own sheep don't go missing!' </fable>
    <fable>A shepherd found a new-born wolf cub. Taking it home, he raised it with his dogs. After the cub had grown up, he would join the dogs in the chase if a prowling wolf ever stole one of the sheep. When the dogs were no longer able to keep up with the other wolf and turned back for home (as sometimes happened), the wolf would continue the chase until he caught the other wolf and received an equal share of the prey, true to his wolf's nature. Then he too would go back home. If, however, no wolves came to seize the sheep, he would secretly slaughter one of the sheep and eat it together with the dogs. When the shepherd finally guessed what was happening, he hanged the wolf from a tree and killed him. </fable>
    <fable>There was a blind man who was in the habit of identifying any animal that was placed in his hands by touching it. Once they gave him a wolf cub. Even after stroking the animal he was not sure of its identity, so he said, 'I am not sure whether it is the cub of a wolf or a fox or some similar creature, but I do know that this is not the kind of animal that should accompany a flock of sheep!' </fable>
    <fable>A wolf followed along after a flock of sheep without doing them any harm. At first the shepherd kept his eye on the wolf as a potential enemy to the flock and never let him out of his sight. But as the wolf continued to accompany the shepherd and did not make any kind of attempt to raid the flock, the shepherd eventually began to regard the wolf more as a guardian of the flock than as a threat. Then, when the shepherd happened to have to go to town, he commended the sheep to the wolf in his absence. The wolf seized his chance and attacked the sheep, slaughtering most of the flock. When the shepherd came back and saw that his flock had been utterly destroyed, he said, 'It serves me right! How could I have ever trusted my sheep to a wolf?' </fable>
    <fable>A man was gathering his sheep into the fold one evening and was about to enclose a tawny wolf inside with the flock. When the dog saw what he was doing, he said to the man, 'How can you be serious about protecting the sheep when you are introducing this creature among us?'</fable>
    <fable>Once upon a time the oak trees came to Zeus and lodged a complaint, 'O Zeus, founder of our species and father of all plant life, if it is our destiny to be chopped down, why did you even cause us to grow?' Zeus smiled and replied, 'It is you yourselves who supply the means of your destruction: if you didn't create all the handles, no farmer would have an axe in his house!'</fable>
    <fable>When a man had made an axe, he asked the trees to give him a handle made of the hardest wood. The other trees selected the wood of the wild olive. The man took the handle and fitted it to his axe. Then, without a moment's hesitation, he began to chop down the trees' mighty branches and trunks, taking whatever he wanted. The oak tree then said to the ash, 'It serves us right, since we gave our enemy the handle he asked for!' </fable>
    <fable>Some woodcutters splitting a wild pine tree drove wedges into the trunk, prying it apart and thus making their work easier. The pine tree groaned and said, 'I cannot blame the axe, who had no connection with my root, but these utterly despicable wedges are my own children. Pounded into me this way and that, they are going to tear me apart!' </fable>
    <fable>An archer aimed at an eagle and let loose an arrow. The eagle was struck and as he turned and looked at the shaft which was tipped with his own feathers, he said, 'Many are betrayed by the very things that they themselves have wrought.'</fable>
    <fable>A bird catcher laid out his net, tying some tame doves to the net as decoys. He then stood off at a distance, waiting to see what would happen. Some wild doves flew up to the tame doves and became entangled in the knots of the net. When the bird catcher ran up and began to grab them, the wild doves got angry at the tame doves, since the tame doves had not warned them about the trap even though they were all members of the same species. The tame doves replied, 'Nevertheless, it is better for us to protect the interests of our masters than to please our relations.' </fable>
    <fable>A bird catcher had captured a partridge and was ready to strangle her right there on the spot. The partridge wanted to save her life so she pleaded with the bird catcher and said, 'If you release me from this snare, I will lure many partridges here and bring them to you.' The bird catcher was made even more angry by this and he killed the partridge immediately. </fable>
    <fable>A wolf swallowed a bone which got stuck in his throat. The pain was excruciating, so the wolf started looking for someone who could be induced to remove the accursed thing in exchange for a reward. The wolf asked each of the animals if they would help him and finally the crane was convinced by the wolf's solemn promises. Trusting her long beak to the wolf's gaping maw, the crane carried out the dangerous cure. Yet when the crane demanded the promised reward, the wolf simply said, 'You ungrateful creature! You extracted your head unharmed from my mouth and still you ask for a reward?'</fable>
    <fable>There was a horse who was the sole owner of a meadow. Then a stag came and wreaked havoc in the meadow. The horse wanted to get revenge, so he asked a certain man if he would help him carry out a vendetta against the stag. The man agreed, provided that the horse took the bit in his mouth so that the man could ride him, wielding his javelin. The horse consented, and the man climbed on his back but instead of getting his revenge, the horse simply became a slave to the man.</fable>
    <fable>The cranes were making trouble for the farmer by snatching the seed he had scattered on the ground. There was a stork who associated with the cranes and lived together with them although he never did any harm to the farmer. When the farmer was fed up with the damage being done to his crops, he prepared a snare and captured the stork together with the cranes. Thus the stork was actually held accountable for crimes he had never committed. </fable>
    <fable>Some swans and some geese became friends and went out onto the meadows. As they were feeding contentedly together, they were discovered by hunters. The swans, owing to the swiftness of their bodies, were immediately able to take wing and fly away. The geese, however, were naturally more heavy and so they were left behind and caught by the hunters. </fable>
    <fable>An eagle flew up to a lion and asked him to be his partner. 'I don't see why not,' replied the lion. 'But first you must give me your long wing-feathers as a pledge that you will keep your promise. How will I be able to trust you as a friend if you do not stay here with me?'</fable>
    <fable>The hares were at war with an eagle and they asked the foxes to be their allies. The foxes said in reply, 'We would agree to be your allies, if we didn't know what sort of creatures you are and who you are fighting against!' </fable>
    <fable>The banks of a river caved in, tossing two pots into the river where they were swept away together in the raging waters. Each of the pots had been created by a different technique from a different material: one was made of poured bronze and the other was moulded clay. There was thus an uneasy alliance between the two of them, one fragile and one unbreakable, as they moved along the winding course of the wandering stream. The bronze jar solemnly promised to keep her hulking progress at a distance from the other jar, not wanting to strike and shatter her. The jar of clay, meanwhile, was afraid that the heavier object might do damage to her lighter frame, because something slight can put no trust in something superior. 'Although your words are reassuring,' the clay pot said, 'I cannot shake this fear from my soul. Whether the wave crashes me into you or you into me, in either case I will be the only victim of the catastrophe.'</fable>
    <fable>A stork had gone to her usual pond and saw a goose there who kept plunging down deep into the water. The stork then asked the goose what she was doing and the goose replied, 'We geese go down into the muddy bottom of the pond to look for food and to escape the hawk's attack.' The stork said, 'I am stronger than the hawk! You should be friends with me, and I will allow you to scoff at that other bird!' The goose agreed, and not long afterwards she called on the stork to come help her. The goose had not plunged into the water, so the hawk immediately swooped down and caught her up in his talons. As the hawk was about to devour her, the goose replied, 'A wretched death awaits anyone who puts his trust in such a worthless defender!' </fable>
    <fable>There was a viper who used to go to a certain spring in order to drink but he was driven away by a water-snake who was furious that the viper would not just stay on his own turf instead of encroaching on the water-snake's territory. Their dispute grew more and more fierce and finally the two of them decided to fight it out, agreeing that both the water and the land would be awarded to the winner. When the day for the fight had been decided, the frogs came to the viper and, since they hated the water-snake, they offered to be his allies and come to his aid during the battle. But when the battle began and the viper grappled with the water-snake, the frogs just sat there croaking, since they were not able to do anything else. In the end, the viper was victorious but he was furious with the frogs since they had failed to come to his aid as they had promised and, what was worse, they had sat there singing songs while he was doing battle. The frogs then said to the viper, 'But you should have known that we had nothing to offer you except the sound of our voices!' </fable>
    <fable>A lion was wandering on the seashore when he saw a dolphin stick his head out of the water. The lion invited the dolphin to become his ally, explaining that they were perfectly suited to befriend and assist one another, given that the dolphin was the king of the sea creatures, while the lion ruled all the animals of the land. The dolphin agreed. Later on, the lion, who had long been at war with the wild bull, asked the dolphin for help. Although he wanted to help, the dolphin was unable to come out of the sea. The lion then reproached the dolphin for having betrayed him. The dolphin said in reply, 'I am not to blame! My nature is that of a sea creature, and it means that I cannot come out onto the land.' </fable>
    <fable>The bear, the lion, and the fox went hunting together. While the lion and the bear tracked down their prey by their own efforts, the fox instead found a camel who had been tied to a post. She then went and told her companions that this was something they could catch.</fable>
    <fable>An eagle was sitting sadly in her tree when she was joined by a kite. The kite said to the eagle, 'Why do I see you looking so sad?' The eagle replied, 'I cannot help but be sad at heart, since I need a mate who is my equal but I cannot find one anywhere.' The kite then said to the eagle, 'You should marry me! I am even stronger than you are, which makes me the ideal bird for you.' The eagle asked him, 'Just what kinds of prey are you able to catch?' The kite said, 'Well, on several occasions I have managed to capture an ostrich in my talons and eat it.' When she heard this, the eagle accepted the kite's proposal and married him. After the wedding ceremony and festivities were finished, the eagle said to the kite, 'Go and get us some of that prey which you promised.' The high-flying kite was only able to offer the eagle a nasty little mouse whose flesh was all putrid and rotten. The eagle said, 'Is this what you promised?' The kite replied, 'In order to make this most eminent match with you, I had no choice but to agree to anything you asked, even if it meant promising something impossible.' </fable>
    <fable>Some castrated sheep had been gathered together in a flock with the rams. Although the sheep realized that the butcher had come into the flock, they pretended not to see him. Even when they saw one of their own seized by the butcher's deadly hands and taken away to be slaughtered, still the sheep were not afraid. Foolishly, they said to one another, 'He keeps his hands off me, he keeps his hands off you; let him take whom he takes.' In the end, there was only one sheep left. This is what he reportedly said to the butcher when he saw that he too was about to be taken away: 'We deserve to be slaughtered one after another since we didn't realize what was happening until it was too late. The fact is, as soon as we saw you here in our midst, back when we were all together, we should have killed you at once by smashing you between our horns.' </fable>
    <fable>A lion was attacking two bulls, hoping to make a meal of them. The bulls, however, both opposed the lion with their horns. Once they had taken their stand, the bulls did not allow the lion to come between them. When the lion saw that he was powerless against the two bulls together, he slyly spoke to one of them and said, 'If you hand your partner over to me, I will keep you safe from harm.' In this way, he was able to seize both of the bulls.</fable>
    <fable>During the war of the dogs and the wolves, the dog-assembly chose an Achaean to be their commander. Although he was an expert in the art of war, the commander waited and delayed. With fierce threats, the dogs urged him to advance and to engage in battle but the commander explained, 'Here is the reason why I delay and act with caution! One must always make plans with an eye to the future. All of the enemy whom I have seen are wolves, members of the same breed, whereas some of us are dogs from Crete, some are Molossian hounds, some are Acarnanians, others are Dolopians, while others boast of being from Cyprus or Thrace. Still others come from other places -- what need is there to go on at length? We are not even the same colour, as the wolves are: some of us are black, some are grey, some are red with white-spotted chests, and some of us are white all over. How can I lead troops who are so lacking in unity to fight against an enemy who all resemble each other in every possible way?'</fable>
    <fable>In summertime, when the heat makes everyone thirsty, a lion and a wild boar had come to drink from the same small spring. They began to argue about who was going to take the first drink, and their argument escalated into a duel to the death. When they momentarily paused to catch their breath, the lion and the boar saw that vultures were waiting to snatch and devour the one who was killed. At that point, the lion and the boar put their hatred aside and said, 'It is better for us to befriend one another than to be eaten by vultures and ravens!' </fable>
    <fable>A lion and a bear had found a fawn and were fighting to see who would keep it. In the protracted violence of the battle, they had both grown faint from fighting so they called a truce in order to rest. Meanwhile, there was a fox who had been pacing around them in circles. When she saw that they had fallen to the ground with the fawn lying between them, she dashed up, grabbed the fawn and took off at a run. The lion and the bear were not even able to get to their feet, so they sat there watching the fox disappear. 'What fools we are,' they said, 'for having gone to so much trouble on that fox's behalf!' </fable>
    <fable>A snake and a weasel were fighting with one another inside a house. The mice who lived in the house were always being hunted down by either the snake or the weasel, so when they saw the snake and the weasel fighting with each other, they emerged from their holes and scurried around. When the weasel and the snake saw what was happening, they stopped fighting with each other and turned their attention to the mice. </fable>
    <fable>A donkey and a mule were walking along together. When the donkey saw that they were carrying equal loads, he got angry and complained that the mule was awarded a double portion of food even though she carried a load that was no bigger than his own. After they had journeyed a little further down the road, the driver saw that the donkey could not hold up under the weight, so he took part of the donkey's load and placed it on the mule. Later, when the driver saw that the donkey had grown even more tired, he again transferred some of the donkey's load to the mule, and so on. Finally the driver took the entire load and shifted it from the donkey to the mule. At that point the mule glanced over at the donkey and said, 'What do you say now: don't I deserve a double portion of food?' </fable>
    <fable>A donkey and an ox had been yoked together to pull a single load. The ox was making a great effort, even though he had an injury to his horn, while the donkey was doing nothing to help. As the ox struggled to pull the load by himself, he soon died. The driver then loaded the ox's carcass upon the donkey and began beating him mercilessly. The donkey broke down and collapsed under the weight, dropping dead in the middle of the road. A flock of birds flew up and alighted on the donkey's carcass. 'If only you had been kind enough to help the ox pull the load,' they said, 'you would not have died this untimely death, with carrion birds feasting on your flesh.'</fable>
    <fable>Back when all the parts of the human body did not function in unison as is the case today, each member of the body had its own opinion and was able to speak. The various members were offended that everything won by their hard work and diligent efforts was delivered to the stomach while he simply sat there in their midst, fully at ease and just enjoying the delights that were brought to him. Finally, the members of the body revolted: the hands refused to bring food to the mouth, the mouth refused to take in any food, and the teeth refused to chew anything. In their angry effort to subdue the stomach with hunger, the various parts of the body and the whole body itself completely wasted away. As a result, they realized that the work done by the stomach was no small matter, and that the food he consumed was no more than what he gave back to all the parts of the body in the form of blood which allows us to flourish and thrive, since the stomach enriches the blood with digested food and then distributes it equally throughout the veins.</fable>
    <fable>A sheep once said to the shepherd, 'You shear us and keep all the wool for yourself; you like to take our milk and make it into cheese; thanks to our children, your flocks flourish and prosper. Yet there is no profit for us in these things. Everything we eat comes from the ground -- and what kind of blossom is there to be found on the mountain sides? The grass is dry even when covered with dew. Meanwhile, you nourish this dog in our midst, feeding her on the same kind of hearty food that you yourself eat!' When the dog heard this, she said, 'If it weren't for me protecting you on every side, you would not even manage to get enough grass to eat! By running all around you, I ward off the marauding thief and the prowling wolf.'</fable>
    <fable>There was a man who had two dogs. He taught one to hunt and the other to be a watchdog. Whenever the hunting dog caught something, the watchdog would also share in the spoils. This made the hunting dog angry at the watchdog, since he had to work for everything he had while the watchdog lived off the fruits of his labour without doing anything. The watchdog retorted, 'Don't blame me! It's our master's fault. Since he didn't teach me how to work, I only know how to eat the food that others earn.'</fable>
    <fable>While he was wandering in the fields, a lion got a thorn stuck in his paw. He immediately went to a shepherd, wagging his tail as he said, 'Don't be afraid! I have come to ask your help; I'm not looking for food.' The lion then lifted his paw and placed it in the man's lap. The shepherd pulled out the thorn from the lion's paw and the lion went back into the woods. Later on, the shepherd was falsely accused of a crime and at the next public games he was released from jail and thrown to the beasts. As the wild animals rushed upon him from all sides, the lion recognized that this was the same man who had healed him. Once again the lion raised his paw and placed it in the shepherd's lap. When the king understood what had happened, he commanded that the lion be spared and that the gentle shepherd be sent back home to his family. </fable>
    <fable>Some field-mice were playing in the woods where a lion was sleeping when one of the mice accidentally ran over the lion. The lion woke up and immediately grabbed the wretched little mouse with his paw. The mouse begged for mercy, since he had not meant to do the lion any harm. The lion decided that to kill such a tiny creature would be a cause for reproach rather than glory, so he forgave the mouse and let him go. A few days later, the lion fell into a pit and was trapped. He started to roar, and when the mouse heard him, he came running. Recognizing the lion in the trap, the mouse said to him, 'I have not forgotten the kindness that you showed me!' The mouse then began to gnaw at the cords binding the lion, cutting through the strands and undoing the clever ingenuity of the hunter's art. The mouse was thus able to restore the lion to the woods, setting him free from his captivity. </fable>
    <fable>An ant was thirsty and went down to a spring expecting to take a drink of water, but instead he found himself in danger of drowning. A pigeon snapped off a leaf from a nearby tree and threw it to the ant so that he could save himself by climbing up onto the leaf. Meanwhile, a bird catcher showed up and prepared his limed reeds, intending to capture the pigeon. The ant then bit the bird catcher on the foot which caused the bird catcher to shake his limed reeds, warning the pigeon who flew off to safety. </fable>
    <fable>A snake and an eagle were grappling with one another as they fought. The snake had tightened his hold on the eagle when a farmer saw them and freed the eagle from the grip of the snake. The snake was angry about what had happened, so he went and poisoned the man's drinking water. But just as the unsuspecting farmer was about to take a drink, the eagle flew down and snatched the cup out of his hands. </fable>
    <fable>An eagle was caught by a farmer but the farmer let him go when he realized what he had caught. The eagle did not forget this good deed, and when he saw the farmer sitting under a wall that was on the verge of collapsing, he snatched the bandana from the man's head, wanting to rouse the man from his seat and make him stand up. After the man set off in pursuit, the kindly eagle dropped what he had snatched and thus fully repaid the man's good deed: the man would have been crushed by the wall's collapse if he had stayed there any longer. After a while the man came back to where he had been sitting and found that the upright section of the wall had fallen to the ground. </fable>
    <fable>In the house of a certain farmer there lived a snake who regularly came to the table and was fed on scraps of food. Not long afterwards the farmer grew rich, but then he became angry at the snake and tried to attack him with an axe. The farmer then lost his wealth and he realized that he had prospered because of the good luck he had gained from the snake before having wounded him. The farmer then begged the snake to forgive him for his evil deed, and the snake replied, 'You are sorry for what you have done, but you must not expect me to be your faithful friend until this scar heals. It is not possible for me to be truly reconciled to you until all thought of that treacherous axe has left my mind.' </fable>
    <fable>There was a snake who used to lurk around the front door of a farmer's house. One day the snake struck the man's son, biting him on the foot. The boy died on the spot. The boy's parents were filled with immense sorrow and the grief-stricken father seized his axe and tried to kill the malevolent snake. When the snake fled his pursuer, the man hurried after him, raising his weapon, determined to strike, but as the farmer was about to deal the snake a deadly blow, he missed and managed only to cut off the tip of his tail. The man was terrified at the thought that he might have killed the snake, so he took cakes and water along with honey and salt and called to the snake, wanting to make peace with him. The snake, however, only hissed softly at the farmer from where he had hidden himself in the rocks and said: 'Man, do not trouble yourself any longer: there can be no possible friendship between us any more. When I look upon my tail, I am in pain. The same is true for you: whenever you look again upon the grave of your son, you will not be able to live in peace with me.' </fable>
    <fable>A panther foolishly happened to have fallen into a pit. The local villagers saw her there and some of them attacked her with sticks or pelted her with stones. There were others who felt sorry for the creature since she seemed sure to die even though she had not done any harm, so they brought her bread to keep up her strength. Night fell and everyone went home, confident that they would find the panther dead when the next day dawned. However, as soon as she recovered from her weakness and regained her strength, the panther escaped from the pit with a mighty leap and hurried quickly home to her den. A few days later she descended upon the village, slaughtering the sheep and even killing the shepherds as she laid waste to everything around her in a furious attack of rage. At this point even the people who had shown mercy to the beast began to fear what lay in store for them. Without a word about the damage that the panther had wrought, they begged her just to spare their lives. The panther then said, 'I am well aware of who pelted me with stones and who gave me bread, so put aside your fears. I have returned as an enemy only to those who wanted to hurt me.'</fable>
    <fable>A gardener had a dog who had fallen into a well. The gardener lowered himself down into the well to pull the dog out, but the dog only gave the man a nasty bite, thinking that the man intended to plunge him even deeper into the water. After the dog had bitten him, the gardener said, 'It serves me right for making such an effort to pull you out of the well, when all you can do is attack me.' </fable>
    <fable>A shepherd had driven his sheep into a stand of oaks. He then spread his cloak under an oak tree and climbed up into the tree in order to shake the acorns down. As the sheep ate the acorns, they also ate the shepherd's cloak, unbeknownst to the shepherd. The shepherd then climbed down from the tree and when he saw what had happened, he said, 'Oh you wicked creatures! You give wool to other people so that they can make clothes but you take my clothes and ruin them, even though I am the one who feeds you!' </fable>
    <fable>A thief got into a beekeeper's property when its owner was away and stole the honeycombs. When the owner came back and saw that the beehives were empty, he stood there puzzling over what had happened. The bees then came back from their pastures and when they found the beekeeper there, they attacked him fiercely with their stings. The beekeeper said to the bees, 'You wretched creatures! You let the man who stole your honeycombs get away with impunity while you direct your rage at me, the very person who takes care of you!' </fable>
    <fable>A deer who was being pursued by hunters hid under a grapevine. When the hunters had passed by, she turned her head and began to eat the leaves of the vine. One of the hunters turned and when he saw the deer, he hurled his javelin and struck her. As she was dying, the deer groaned to herself, 'It serves me right, since I injured the vine that saved me!' </fable>
    <fable>There was a nut tree standing by the side of the road who had a great many nuts and the people walking along the road used to knock them off by throwing sticks and stones at the tree. The nut tree then said sadly, 'Woe is me! People gladly enjoy my fruits, but they have a terrible way of showing their gratitude.' </fable>
    <fable>Around noon on a summer's day, some travellers who were exhausted by the heat caught sight of a plane tree. They went and lay down in the shade of the tree in order to rest. Looking up at the tree, they remarked to one another that the plane tree produced no fruit and was therefore useless to mankind. The plane tree interrupted them and said, 'What ungrateful people you are! You denounce my uselessness and lack of fruit at the very moment in which you are enjoying my kindness!' </fable>
    <fable>An eagle was once caught by a man who immediately clipped his wings and turned him loose in the house with the chickens. The eagle was utterly dejected and grief-stricken. Another man bought the eagle and restored the eagle's feathers. The eagle then soared on his outspread wings and seized a hare, which he promptly brought back as a gift for the man who had rescued him. A fox saw what the eagle was doing and shouted, 'He's not the one who needs your attention! You should give the hare to the first man, so that if he ever catches you again, he won't deprive you of your wing feathers like the first time.' </fable>
    <fable>A man was riding a pregnant mare and she gave birth to her foal while they were still on the road. The new-born foal followed directly behind his mother but soon became unsteady on his feet. The foal then said to the man, 'Look, you can see that I am very small and not strong enough to travel. If you leave me here, I am sure to die. But if you carry me away from here back to your home and bring me up, then later on, when I am grown, I shall let you ride me.' </fable>
    <fable>On his travels, Diogenes the Cynic came to a stream that was flooded. He stood on the bank, unable to go any farther. One of those ferrymen who regularly carry people across rivers saw that Diogenes did not know what to do so he approached the philosopher, picked him up, and kindly carried him across the water. Diogenes then stood on the opposite shore, bewailing the poverty that prevented him from rewarding the man for his good deed. While Diogenes was still pondering this state of affairs, the ferryman saw another traveller who could not get across, so he ran off to offer his assistance. Diogenes accosted the ferryman and said, 'Well, I do not feel in your debt any longer for the favour that you did me. This is not an act of judgment on your part - it's an addiction!' </fable>
    <fable>A fox was standing not far from a trap, pondering every possible approach. A nearby wolf noticed the fox and approached her. He then asked the fox if he might be allowed to take the meat, and the fox replied, 'Go ahead and help yourself! You're welcome to it, seeing as you are one of my very dearest friends.' The wolf rushed up without a moment's hesitation and as he learned forward over the trap he released the trigger so that the rod sprang free, striking his snout and forehead. 'If this is the sort of gift you give you to your friends,' said the wolf, 'why would anyone ever want to be your friend?'</fable>
    <fable>A bird-catcher had set up his snare for the birds. A lark observed these preparations and asked the bird-catcher what he was doing. The man said to the lark that he was founding a city. The man then moved away from the snare. The bird, believing what the man had said, approached and ate some of the bait. Then, without realizing it, he was trapped in the snare. As the bird-catcher ran up and grabbed hold of the lark, the bird said to him, 'Look here, if this is the sort of city you are founding, you won't find many inhabitants for it!' </fable>
    <fable>A man saw a dog walking by and threw him some bits of food. The dog then said to the man, 'O man, keep away from me! All your well-wishing warns me to be even more on my guard.' </fable>
    <fable>A man saw a dog walking by and threw him some bits of food. The dog then said to the man, 'O man, keep away from me! All your well-wishing warns me to be even more on my guard.' </fable>
    <fable>A deer had fallen ill and was resting on the grassy plain. When the other animals came to see her, they ate up all the grass in her pasture. As a result, when the deer recovered from her illness, she ended up dying since her pasture had come to an end. </fable>
    <fable>A man was travelling together with his friend along a narrow road through unknown mountains and winding valleys. He felt safe because he and his friend could combine forces to fight whatever danger Fortune might put in their way. As they were travelling along discussing various subjects, a bear suddenly confronted them in the middle of the road. One of the men ran straight for a tree and grabbed at a branch in order to suspend his trembling body in the foliage. The other man stood stock still and then fell to the ground on purpose, pretending to be dead. The wild beast immediately ran up to him, eager to seize her victim. With her curved bear claws, she lifted the wretched man up off the ground, but since his limbs had grown stiff and frozen with fear (for the usual warmth of life had left his body), the bear concluded that he was nothing but a rotting corpse. Thus, despite her hunger, the bear abandoned the man and went away to her den. The men gradually began to relax and started up their conversation again. The man who had only just now fled in fear was feeling far too sure of himself and he said to his companion, 'Tell me, my friend, what did that bear say to you while you were lying there shaking? She must have told you many things in that lengthy private conversation.' The other man replied, 'Indeed, she gave me some quite important advice including, alas, one particular command that I cannot afford to forget: Do not be too quick to resume your fellowship with that other man, in case you fall once again into the clutches of another wild beast.'</fable>
    <fable>Two soldiers happened to fall into the clutches of a robber: one of the soldiers ran away while the other stood his ground and defended himself with all the strength he could muster. As soon as the robber had been beaten back, the soldier's cowardly companion ran up, drawing his sword and even throwing aside his cloak as he said 'Let me at him; I will make sure he knows who it is he has dared to attack!' The one who had fought with the robber replied, 'I only wish that you had been here to help me with your words; even if you did nothing more than that, I would have believed what you were saying and would have fought with even greater determination. But please put away your sword and shut your useless mouth: you might be able to fool people who do not know you, but I have learned by experience with what prowess you turn tail and run, and how unreliable your courage really is.' </fable>
    <fable>Two men were walking down the same road together when one of them found an axe. 'Eureka!' he cried, 'I found it!' The one who didn't find the axe said to him, 'Don't say "I found it" -- say "we found it" instead.' A little while later the people who had lost the axe caught up with them, and when they started to chase the man who was holding the axe, he said to his fellow traveller, 'We are lost!' The fellow traveller answered, 'Incorrect! You should say "I am lost," not "we are lost," since when you found the axe and you said "I" found it, not "we" found it.' </fable>
    <fable>Socrates had erected for himself a very modest house - and I myself would even be willing to die as Socrates died if I could achieve an equal fame, yes, I would be willing to suffer the same public disapproval if I too could be vindicated after death! Anyway, just as you would expect on such an occasion, one of his neighbours had to ask, 'Why is it, Socrates, that someone like you would build himself such a tiny little house?' 'Ah,' said Socrates, 'if only I could fill it with true friends!'</fable>
    <fable>The cat pretended that it was his birthday and invited the birds to a party. When the birds had come in, the cat seized the opportunity: he shut the doors of his house and proceeded to devour the birds one after another. </fable>
    <fable>The raven pretended that it was his birthday and invited the birds to a party. Once the birds were inside, he locked the door and began to kill them one by one. </fable>
    <fable>The cricket was making a great deal of noise and this greatly annoyed the owl, since she was accustomed to seek out her food in the darkness of night and to sleep during the day inside the hollowed-out branch of a tree. The owl thus asked the cricket to keep quiet, which only provoked the cricket to make an even greater racket. Again the owl asked the cricket to keep quiet, and this triggered a still greater outburst of noise. When the owl saw that she was accomplishing nothing since the cricket simply scorned her requests, she decided to trick the chattering insect. 'Given that I cannot sleep because of your singing,' said the owl, 'which of course one might easily mistake for the tuneful strains of Apollo's lyre, I've decided to drink some of the nectar which Athena recently gave me as a gift. Please come and let's drink it together, if that meets with your approval.' The cricket happened to be extremely thirsty and she was also quite pleased by the compliments which the owl had paid to her singing, so she gladly flew to where the owl was waiting. The owl then sealed up the entrance and seized the trembling cricket and brought an end to her life: what the cricket refused to do while living, she conceded in death.</fable>
    <fable>A night-owl asked a cat if the cat would agree to carry him around, so that together they could go look for someone to talk to. The cat took the owl to the house of a mouse. The owl asked the cat to announce him and he did so. When the mouse heard the voice of the cat, he came to the door of his house and said, 'What do you two want from me? What do you have to say?' 'We want to talk with you,' said the owl and the cat. The mouse understood that these two had devised some evil plot against him, so he replied, 'A curse on you, my lord cat, and a curse on the one you are carrying-- and a curse on your house, and on your sons and your daughters, and on all your damn relatives! You did badly to come here, and I hope that bad things will befall you on your way back home!' </fable>
    <fable>A night-owl asked a cat if the cat would agree to carry him around, so that together they could go look for someone to talk to. The cat took the owl to the house of a mouse. The owl asked the cat to announce him and he did so. When the mouse heard the voice of the cat, he came to the door of his house and said, 'What do you two want from me? What do you have to say?' 'We want to talk with you,' said the owl and the cat. The mouse understood that these two had devised some evil plot against him, so he replied, 'A curse on you, my lord cat, and a curse on the one you are carrying-- and a curse on your house, and on your sons and your daughters, and on all your damn relatives! You did badly to come here, and I hope that bad things will befall you on your way back home!' </fable>
    <fable>There was a goat grazing up high on a cliff. At the bottom of the cliff there was a wolf who wanted to catch the goat and eat her. Since it was impossible for the wolf to climb up the cliff, he stood down below and said to the goat, 'You poor creature! Why have you left the level plains and meadows in order to graze upon the cliff? Are you trying to tempt death from that height?' The goat said to the wolf in response, 'I know how often I have managed to frustrate you! What makes you think that you can now get me to come down off this cliff so that you can eat me for dinner?' </fable>
</aesop>